Register of the Scientists For Sakharov, Orlov And Shcharansky Records, 1975-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
- Chairman's File, 1978-1997.
  - Correspondence
    - IBM Research Center, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Independent Gazette, 1979 (Folder 2)
    - Institute for Advanced Study, 1981-1984 (Folder 3)
    - Institute of Chemical Physics, 1987 (Folder 4)
    - Institute of Nuclear Physics, 1991 (Folder 5)
    - Instituto de Pesquisas Espaciais, 1980 (Folder 6)
    - Instituto Tecnológico de Aeronáutica, 1980 (Folder 7)
    - Instituto Venezolano de Investigaciones Cientificas, 1980 (Folder 8)
    - International Campaign-Massera, Includes materials relating to the imprisonment and subsequent release of Jose Luis Massera, 1983-1984. (Folder 9)
    - International Campaign: Orlov & Shcharansky, 1984 (Folder 10)
    - International Coalition of Scientists for Sakharov, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov, 1981 (Folder 12)
    - International Federation of Automatic Control (IFAC), 1984 (Folder 13)
    - International Sakharov Conference on Physics (1st:: Moscow, Russia), 1990-1991 (Folder 14)
    - International Sakharov Hearing (5th:: London), 1985 (Folder 15)
    - International Sakharov Tribute Dinner, 1984 (Folder 16)
    - Intrator, Genya, 1992 (Folder 17)
    - Israel. Embassy (United States), 1980 (Folder 18)
    - Istituto di Fisica "Guglielmo Marconi,", 1983 (Folder 19)
    - Istituto Nazionale di Fisica Nucleare, 1980-1989 (Folder 20)
    - J. M. Kaplan Fund, 1982 (Folder 21)
    - Jacobson, ?, 1978 (Folder 22)
    - Jewish Bulletin, 1983 (Folder 23)
    - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1987 (Folder 24)
    - Johns Hopkins University, 1978-1986 (Folder 25)
    - Jolly, Jon B., Inc., 1979 (Folder 26)
    - Joyce Mertz-Gilmore Foundation, 1982 (Folder 27)
    - Karolinska Institutet, 1984 (Folder 28)
    - KCBS, 1986 (Folder 29)
    - KEK, 1984 (Folder 30)
    - Khachaturyan, Armen, n.d. (Folder 31)
    - Kiernan, Bruce Alan, 1982 (Folder 32)
    - Kline Brothers Company, 1982-1991 (Folder 33)
    - KQED, 1984 (Folder 34)
    - Kramer, Genevieve, 1979 (Folder 35)
    - La Jolla Institute, 1982 (Folder 36)
    - Laber, Jeri, Ms?, 1980 (Folder 37)
    - Laguna, Frederica de, 1984 (Folder 38)
    - LASL, 1980 (Folder 39)
    - Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, 1984 (Folder 40)
    - Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights, 1983 (Folder 41)
    - Lebedev Physical Institute, 1990-1991 (Folder 42)
    - Lehigh University, 1984 (Folder 43)
    - Levin, Marty, n.d. (Folder 44)
    - Linkabit Corporation, 1978 (Folder 45)
    - Lipkin, Malka, 1986 (Folder 46)
    - Lithuanian Information Center, 1990 (Folder 47)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1978-1984 (Folder 48)
    - Lwoff, André, 1984 (Folder 49)
    - McCracken, Daniel D., 1978-1980 (Folder 50)
    - McGill University, 1979-1997 (Folder 51)
    - Mailing Management Inc., 1985 (Folder 52)
    - Manekofsky, Irene, 1979 (Folder 53)
    - Marin County Human Resources Office, 1992 (Folder 54)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1978-1981 (Folder 55)
    - Mathieu, J. P., 1982 (Folder 56)
    - Max-Planck-Institut für Biophysikalische Chemie, 1978 (Folder 57)
    - Max-Planck-Institut für Verhaltensphysiologie, 1980 (Folder 58)
    - MCI World Message Service, 1991 (Folder 59)
    - Medical and Science Communications DevelopmentCorporation, 1984 (Folder 60)
    - Meisei University, 1980 (Folder 61)
    - Metcalfe, Robin, 1988 (Folder 62)
    - Meyer, Gary & Linda, 1978 (Folder 63)
    - Meyer, Henry J., 1986 (Folder 64)
    - Migdal, Diana, 1992 (Folder 65)
    - Morini, Alice, 1982 (Folder 66)
    - Mother Jones, 1978 (Folder 67)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1979-1985 (Folder 68)
    - National Bureau of Standards, 1978 (Folder 69)
    - National Council of Education, 1980 (Folder 70)
    - National Institute of Health, 1979-1986 (Folder 71)
    - National Institute of Environmental Health Science, 1979 (Folder 72)
    - National Radio Astronomy Observatory, 1984 (Folder 73)
    - National Research Council, 1986 (Folder 74)
    - Nature, 1980-1986 (Folder 75)
    - Néwitt, Peter, n.d. (Folder 76)
    - Newsweek, 1979 (Folder 77)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1979-1983 (Folder 78)
    - New York Times, 1979-1986 (Folder 79)
    - Northeastern University, 1978 (Folder 80)
    - Northwestern University, n.d. (Folder 81)
    - North Carolina State University, 1978 (Folder 82)
    - Novack, Jena, 1980 (Folder 83)
    - Office for European Office of International Health, 1979 (Folder 84)
    - Ohio State University, 1978 (Folder 85)
    - Olsher, Richard, 1979 (Folder 86)
    - Orloff, Serge, 1984 (Folder 87)
    - Pearl, William S., 1984 (Folder 88)
    - Penzias, Arno A., 1986 (Folder 89)
    - Physics Today, 1980-1984 (Folder 90)
    - Physics Review and Physical Review Letters, 1980 (Folder 91)
    - Pinsky, Stephen, 1979 (Folder 92)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York, 1978 (Folder 93)
    - Le Poulet, 1986 (Folder 94)
    - Powell, Goldstein, Frazer & Murphy, 1986 (Folder 95)
    - Prima Printing, 1980 (Folder 96)
    - Primakoff, ?, 1978 (Folder 97)
    - Princeton University, 1985 (Folder 98)
    - Purdue University, 1979-1980 (Folder 99)
    - Queen Mary College, 1980-1984 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ralston, Anthony, 1980 (Folder 2)
    - Random House, Inc., 1980-1986 (Folder 3)
    - Regional Procurator for Kharkov, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1984 (Folder 5)
    - Rivkin, Lenny, 1984 (Folder 6)
    - Robinson, Berol, 1980 (Folder 7)
    - Robinson, Louis G., See also General Office File, 1981. (Folder 8)
    - Royer, Charles, 1984 (Folder 9)
    - Rutgers University, 1979-1990 (Folder 10)
    - Safir, Zora, 1981-1982 (Folder 11)
    - Saint Olaf College, 1984 (Folder 12)
    - Sakharov International Committee, 1980 (Folder 13)
    - Sakharov Scholarship Fund, 1982 (Folder 14)
    - Sales Promotion Services, Inc., 1982 (Folder 15)
    - San Diego Union, 1978-1979 (Folder 16)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, 1979-1986 (Folder 17)
    - San Francisco Examiner, 1979 (Folder 18)
    - San Francisco State University, 1979-1997 (Folder 19)
    - San Jose Mercury News, 1979-1983 (Folder 20)
    - Scaife Family Charitable Trusts, 1982 (Folder 21)
    - Schwartz, Laurent, 1978 (Folder 22)
    - Science, 1979-1986 (Folder 23)
    - Scientists for the Release of Soviet Refuseniks, 1986 (Folder 24)
    - Senn, Milton A., 1984 (Folder 25)
    - Shcharansky, Avital and Natan (Anatoly B.), See also Sofios, Yael (formerly Michèle), 1986-1990. (Folder 26)
    - Silk, Thomas, 1979 (Folder 27)
    - Smith Richardson Foundation, Inc., 1979-1983 (Folder 28)
    - Sofios, Yael (formerly Michèle), Includes Morris Pripstein's letters jointly addressed to Yael (formerly Michèle)and Avital Shcharansky, 1978-1983. (Folder 29)
    - Southeastern Massachusetts University, 1980 (Folder 30)
    - Soviet Union. Posol'stvo (United States), 1984 (Folder 31)
    - Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, 1979-1982 (Folder 32)
    - Stanford University, 1978-1986 (Folder 33)
    - Stanford University Medical center, 1979-1982 (Folder 34)
    - State University of New York at Albany, 1978-1979 (Folder 35)
    - State University of New York at Buffalo, 1982 (Folder 36)
    - State University of New York at Stony Brook, 1979 (Folder 37)
    - Stichting Mathematisch Centrum, 1978 (Folder 38)
    - Stone, Jeremy, 1979-1982 (Folder 39)
    - Syracuse University, 1978-1983 (Folder 40)
    - Theil, Edward, 1984 (Folder 41)
    - Time Magazine, 1979? (Folder 42)
    - Tulane University, 1980 (Folder 43)
    - Turchin, Valentine, 1981-1986 (Folder 44)
    - Tuvin, Yury, 1980 (Folder 45)
    - Union of Councils for Soviet Jews, 1979-1983 (Folder 46)
    - U.S. News and World Report, 1979 (Folder 47)
    - United Federation of Teachers, 1979-1980 (Folder 48)
    - United States. Congress. House, 1979-1983 (Folder 49)
    - United States. Congress. Senate, 1979-1984 (Folder 50)
    - United States. Department of Commerce, 1979-1980 (Folder 51)
    - United States. Department of Energy, 1979-1981 (Folder 52)
    - United States. Department of Justice, n.d. (Folder 53)
    - United States. Department of State, 1979-1985 (Folder 54)
    - United States. President, 1978-1986 (Folder 55)
    - Università di Milano, 1980 (Folder 56)
    - Universität Hamburg, 1983 (Folder 57)
    - Université de Montréal, 1980-1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Université de Nice, 1980 (Folder 2)
    - Université Laval, 1980 (Folder 3)
    - Université Paris VII, 1978-1982 (Folder 4)
    - University of AARHUS, 1979 (Folder 5)
    - University of Auckland, 1984 (Folder 6)
    - University of Bristol, 1979 (Folder 7)
    - University of California, 1982 (Folder 8)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Includes a letter to Florence Pripstein from Ira Heyman, Chancellor, 1978-1991. (Folder 9)
    - University of California, Irvine, 1981 (Folder 10)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, 1980 (Folder 11)
    - University of California, San Diego, 1978 (Folder 12)
    - University of California Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, 1979 (Folder 13)
    - University of Cambridge, 1979 (Folder 14)
    - University of Canterbury, 1984 (Folder 15)
    - University of Cape Town, 1984 (Folder 16)
    - University of Chicago, 1978 (Folder 17)
    - University of Colorado at Boulder, 1992 (Folder 18)
    - University of Denver, 1981 (Folder 19)
    - University of Durham, 1984 (Folder 20)
    - University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC), 1989 (Folder 21)
    - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 1978-1984 (Folder 22)
    - University of Jyväskylä, 1979 (Folder 23)
    - University of Manchester Institute of Science and Technology, 1979 (Folder 24)
    - University of Maryland, 1978-1985 (Folder 25)
    - University of Massachusetts, Amherst, 1978 (Folder 26)
    - University of Michigan, 1978-1980 (Folder 27)
    - University of Minnesota, 1978-1979 (Folder 28)
    - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1978-1984 (Folder 29)
    - University of Pennsylvania, n.d. (Folder 30)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1979-1985 (Folder 31)
    - University of Rochester, n.d. (Folder 32)
    - University of Rome, 1989 (Folder 33)
    - University of Southern California, n.d. (Folder 34)
    - University of Sussex, 1984 (Folder 35)
    - University of Texas at Austin, 1984 (Folder 36)
    - University of Texas at El Paso, 1983 (Folder 37)
    - University of Tokyo, 1984 (Folder 38)
    - University of Washington, 1978-1980 (Folder 39)
    - University of Wisconsin, Department of Mathematics, 1979 (Folder 40)
    - University of Wisconsin, McArdle Laboratory, 1978-1979 (Folder 41)
    - Upsala College, 1980 (Folder 42)
    - Varian Associates, 1985 (Folder 43)
    - Veklerov, E., 1979 (Folder 44)
    - Velikanov, Cyrille, 1979 (Folder 45)
    - Velle, O'Connor, 1985 (Folder 46)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1983 (Folder 47)
    - Washington Post, 1979-1985 (Folder 48)
    - Washington Research Institute, 1986-1989 (Folder 49)
    - Washington State University, 1980 (Folder 50)
    - Weber, James J., 1983 (Folder 51)
    - Weizenbaum, ?, 1979 (Folder 52)
    - Weizmann Institute of Science, 1982-1983 (Folder 53)
    - Werner Erhard & Associates, 1983 (Folder 54)
    - Wesleyan University, 1984 (Folder 55)
    - West Virginia University, 1978 (Folder 56)
    - Will, George, 1981 (Folder 57)
    - Williams, Marta, 1983 (Folder 58)
    - Wilson, Michael, 1986 (Folder 59)
    - Woodruff Organization, 1980 (Folder 60)
    - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology, 1984 (Folder 61)
    - World Without War Council of Northern California, 1979-1980 (Folder 62)
    - Yale University, 1981-1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Yankelevich, Efrem & Tanya, 1980-1990 (Folder 2)
    - Yarim-Agaev, Yuri, 1986 (Folder 3)
    - Yerevan Physics Institute, 1991 (Folder 4)
    - Yorkin, Bud, 1979 (Folder 5)
    - Zen, E-an, 1984 (Folder 6)
  - Financial records
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Bank statements (Folder 8)
    - Invoices and telephone bills. Includes some letters and memoranda (Folder 9)
    - Payment records (Folder 10)
    - Receipts
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Postal (Folder 12)
    - Miscellany (Folder 13)
  - Flow chart describing the options for SOS (Folder 14)
  - Flyers (Folder 15)
  - Lists (Folder 16)
  - Memoranda
    - Undated (Folder 17)
    - 1978-1980 (Folder 18)
    - 1981 (Folder 19)
    - 1982 (Folder 20)
    - 1983 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1984 (Folder 2)
    - 1985 (Folder 3)
    - 1986 (Folder 4)
    - 1987-1995 (Folder 5)
  - Messages (Folder 6)
  - Minutes of SOS Executive Committee meeting, 1982 January 26 (Folder 7)
  - Newsletters (Folder 8)
  - Notes. Includes "Reagan, Russia, and Human Rights," sponsored by SCOPE, Stanford Hillel, Stanford Catholic Community conference program and conference notes by Morris Pripstein, 1980 (Folder 9-11)
  - Notes (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Press releases (Folder 4)
  - Printed matter (Folder 5-7)
  - Printed matter (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Remarks (Folder 2)
  - Reports. Includes reports from Jack Minker and Florence Pripstein
    - Undated (Folder 3)
    - 1980-1986 (Folder 4)
  - Resolution for a special election to be held throughout the County of Los Angeles (Folder 5)
  - Speech at Sakharov birthday ceremony at City Hall, Berkeley? Outline, 1986 May 29. (Folder 6)
  - Statements (Folder 7)
  - Telegrams (Folder 8)
  - Travel records (Folder 9)
  - Miscellany. Includes photocopies of photographs of Morris Pripstein with Robert Cahn, Dave Jackson, Andrei Sakharov, Andrew Sessler, Tatanya Yankelevich and others (Folder 10)
- Subject File, 1973-1998.
  Includes addresses, articles, brochures, bulletins, clippings, conference proceedings, correspondence, directory, financial records, flyers, itinerary, lists, memoranda, messages, minutes of meetings, newsletters, notes, petitions, press releases, printed matter, remarks, reports, speeches, statements, testimony, transcript, and miscellany related to human rights issues, scientific cooperation, nuclear weapons and arms race, and other issues, arranged alphabetically by subject. See also General Office File and Chairman's File
  - Academy of Sciences of the USSR (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Folder 6-7)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Folder 8-11)
  - American Jewish Committee (Folder 12)
  - American Physical Society (Folder 13-18)
  - Amnesty International (Folder 19-22)
  - Arms race (Folder 23)
  - Association for Computing Machinery (Folder 24-26)
  - Bay Area Council on Soviet Jewry
    - General (Folder 27)
    - Correspondence (Folder 28)
    - Financial records (Folder 29)
    - Flyers (Folder 30)
    - Memoranda (Folder 31)
    - Minutes of meetings (Folder 32)
    - Press releases (Folder 33)
    - Reports (Folder 34)
    - Statements (Folder 35)
    - Miscellany (Folder 36)
  - Bonner, Elena. See also Subject File/Sakharov, Andrei
    - General (Folder 37)
    - Articles (Folder 38)
    - Bulletins (Folder 39)
    - Clippings (Folder 40)
    - Correspondence (Folder 41-42)
    - Flyers (Folder 43)
    - Itinerary (Folder 44)
    - Newsletters and newspapers (Folder 45)
    - Press releases (Folder 46)
    - Printed matter (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Remarks (Folder 2)
    - Reports (Folder 3)
    - Speech. Includes Elena Bonner's authorization to use her speech at the University of California, Berkeley, on for purposes of publication, 1990 March 23 (Folder 4)
    - Miscellany (Folder 5)
  - Center for Democracy in the USSR (Folder 6)
  - Chamberlain, Owen
    - Signatures (Folder 7)
    - Statements (Folder 8)
    - Testimony before the Subcommittee on Investigations of the House Committee on the Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 9)
  - China (Folder 10-17)
  - Coalition for a Democratic Majority (Folder 18)
  - Comité des Physiciens Français. See also Subject File/ Orlov, Yuri (Folder 19-22)
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists, Inc.
    - General (Folder 23)
    - Correspondence (Folder 24)
    - Memoranda (Folder 25)
    - Press releases (Folder 26)
    - Printed matter (Folder 27)
    - Statements (Folder 28)
    - Telegrams (Folder 29)
    - Testimony by Max Gottesman and Dorothy Hirsch (Folder 30)
  - Committee on International Freedom of Scientists (Folder 31)
  - Dole, Robert (Folder 32-33)
  - Federation of American Scientists (Folder 34-35)
  - Feinstein, Diane - Proclamation (Folder 36)
  - Flory, Emily J. (Folder 37)
  - Flory, Paul J.
    - Articles
      - Undated (Folder 38)
      - 1981-1986 (Folder 39)
    - Clippings (Folder 40)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Folder 41)
      - 1979 (Folder 42)
      - 1980 (Folder 43)
      - 1981 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - 1982-1983 (Folder 2)
      - 1984-1985 (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda (Folder 4)
    - Printed matter. Includes a copy of Paul Flory's obituary (Folder 5)
    - Reports (Folder 6)
    - Signatures (Folder 7)
    - Statements (Folder 8)
    - Telegrams (Folder 9)
  - Freedom House (Folder 10-11)
  - Freedom of Communications (Folder 12)
  - Fusion Power Associates (Folder 13)
  - Gordon Research Conference on High Temperature Chemistry: Plymouth, NH), 1980 (Folder 14)
  - Gottfried, Kurt
    - Articles (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Folder 16)
      - 1978-1979 (Folder 17)
      - 1980-1987 (Folder 18)
    - Memoranda (Folder 19)
    - Remarks. Includes an outline on scientific freedom and human rights (Folder 20)
    - Statements
      - Undated (Folder 21)
      - 1978-1981 (Folder 22)
  - Helsinki Watch
    - General (Folder 23)
    - Address directory (Folder 24)
    - Brochures (Folder 25)
    - Correspondence (Folder 26)
    - Flyers (Folder 27)
    - Memoranda (Folder 28)
    - Position paper (Folder 29)
    - Press releases (Folder 30)
    - Recommendations for the Madrid conference (Folder 31)
    - Report on Soviet-American exchange and human (Folder 32)
    - rights
    - Statements on the situation of Yuri Orlov (Folder 33)
    - Miscellany (Folder 34)
  - Human rights. Consists of documents from various individuals and organizations on human rights issues (Box 26)
    - General. Confirmation hearings for the position of Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs (Folder 1)
    - Articles. Includes articles by Earl Callen and others, E. M. Friedlander, and Robert W. Kates (Folder 2)
    - Brochures (Folder 3)
    - Bulletins (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Folder 5)
      - 1977-1978 (Folder 6)
      - 1979-1980 (Folder 7)
      - 1981-1991 (Folder 8)
    - Flyers (Folder 9)
    - Newsletters (Folder 10)
    - Pamphlets (Folder 11)
    - Press releases (Folder 12)
    - Proposal for a Human Rights project group (Folder 13)
    - Remarks (Folder 14)
    - Reports. Includes a report of the Association for Computing Machinery Committee on scientific freedom and human rights edited by Jack Minker (Folder 15)
    - Statements. Includes statements by Soviet dissidents on scientific exchange and human rights, and by Tatiana Yankelevich to SOS reception at Twenty-Third International Conference on High Energy Physics (Folder 16)
  - Institut Iadernoi Fiziki (Akademiia nauk SSSR) (Folder 17)
  - International Conference on Artificial Intelligence (Folder 18)
  - International Quantum Electronics Conference(11th:: Boston, Mass.), 1980 (Folder 19)
  - Jewish Community Relations Council of the Greater East Bay (Folder 20)
  - Jewish Welfare Federation (Folder 21)
  - Lerner, Alexander
    - General (Folder 22)
    - Articles (Folder 23)
    - Correspondence (Folder 24)
    - Messages (Folder 25)
    - Petition (Folder 26)
  - Lipkin, Harry J.
    - Articles on Andrei Sakharov (Folder 27)
    - Correspondence. Includes a letter to Andrei Sakharov (Folder 28)
  - National Academy of Sciences. See also Subject File/ Sakharov, Andrei
    - Bulletins (Folder 29)
    - Correspondence (Folder 30)
    - Membership directory (Folder 31)
    - Memoranda (Folder 32)
    - Press releases (Folder 33)
    - Printed matter (Folder 34)
    - Programs (Folder 35)
    - Report on science and human rights (Folder 36)
    - Resolution asking the Academy of Sciences of the USSR for help to ameliorate the situation of Andrei Sakharov (Folder 37)
  - National Conference on Soviet Jewry (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Folder 4-5)
  - Orlov, Yuri. Includes documents issued by individuals and organizations in defense of Yuri Orlov
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Appeals by Irina Orlova and others on behalf of Yuri Orlov (Folder 7)
    - Articles (Folder 8)
    - Biographical information (Folder 9)
    - Brochures (Folder 10)
    - Bulletins (Folder 11)
    - Clippings (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence (Folder 13-15)
    - Flyers (Folder 16)
    - Memoranda (Folder 17)
    - Messages. Includes messages from Orlov Committee (Folder 18)
    - Minutes of the Orlov Committee meeting (Folder 19)
    - Newsletters (Folder 20)
    - Press releases (Folder 21)
    - Printed matter (Folder 22)
    - Reports. Includes reports by Irina and Yuri Orlov (Folder 23)
    - Schedule for Yuri Orlov's visit (Folder 24)
    - Statements. Includes statements by Yuri Orlov (Folder 25)
  - Physics - International cooperation. See also Subject File/Science - International cooperation (Folder 26-28)
  - Sakharov, Andrei
    - General (Folder 29)
    - Addresses by Elena Bonner and Andrei Sakharov at the commencement ceremony at the College of Staten Island, City University of New York, 1987 June 14 (Folder 30)
    - Appeals on behalf of the Sakharovs (Folder 31)
    - Articles by Andrei Sakharov and others (Folder 32-33)
    - Brochures (Folder 34)
    - Bulletins (Folder 35)
    - Clippings (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (Folder 2-3)
    - Flyers (Folder 4)
    - Memoranda (Folder 5)
    - Messages (Folder 6)
    - Newsletters (Folder 7)
    - Organizational record of the Sakharov International Committee (Folder 8)
    - Petitions on behalf of Andrei Sakharov (Folder 9)
    - Press releases (Folder 10)
    - Printed matter (Folder 11-12)
    - Proceedings of the International Andrei Sakharov Memorial Congress (Folder 13)
    - Proclamation issued by Ronald Reagan (Folder 14)
    - Programs for the International Conferences in Honor of Andrei Sakharov (Folder 15)
    - Remarks by Philip Handler, President, National Academy of Sciences, on the occasion of the International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov (Folder 16)
    - Report by group of experts of the First International Andrei Sakharov Memorial Congress, entitled "Peace, Progress, and Human Rights," on their visit to the Armenian-Azerbaijani border region, 1991 May 25-29 (Folder 17)
    - Statements. Includes a statement by the International Coalition of Scientists for Sakharov (ICSS) (Folder 18)
    - Telegrams. Greetings on Andrei Sakharov's 62nd birthday (Folder 19)
    - Transcripts of the session of the Australian Parliament, 1984 May 30 (Folder 20)
    - Miscellany (Folder 21)
  - Science - International cooperation. See also WRITINGS BY OTHERS (Folder 22-24)
  - Sessler, Andrew M. (Box 29)
    - Articles (Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Folder 2)
      - 1977-1981 (Folder 3)
      - 1982-1989 (Folder 4)
    - Financial records (Folder 5)
    - Itinerary (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda
      - Undated (Folder 7)
      - 1977-1981 (Folder 8)
    - Notes (Folder 9)
    - Press releases (Folder 10)
    - Printed matter (Folder 11)
    - Remarks (Folder 12)
    - Reports (Folder 13)
    - Statements (Folder 14)
    - Telegrams (Folder 15)
    - Miscellany (Folder 16)
  - Shcharansky, Natan (Anatoly B.) and Avital. See also Subject File/Bay Area Council on Soviet Jewry
    - Clippings (Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (Folder 18-19)
    - Flyers (Folder 20)